<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><id>http://www.epics-project.eu/</id><title>EPiCS News</title>
<updated>2014-04-15T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/">
<link rel="self" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/atom.xml">
<author><name>The EPiCS Consortium</name><uri>http://www.epics-project.eu</uri></author><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2014-04-16:/news/2014-04-16-Nebehay-Best-Paper-Award/</id><title type="html">Best paper award for Georg Nebehay and Roman Pflugfelder at WACV'14</title>
<published>2014-04-15T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2014-04-15T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2014-04-16-Nebehay-Best-Paper-Award/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that Georg Nebehay and Roman Pflugfelder, who work on EPiCS at AIT, have receive the best paper award of the &lt;a href="http://www.wacv14.org/"&gt;WACV'14 conference&lt;/a&gt; for their paper &lt;a href="/publications/nebehay14_wacv.pdf"&gt;Consensus-based Matching and Tracking of Keypoints for Object Tracking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="/news/nebehay-voting.png" width="100%" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: left;"&gt;Keypoints (white) vote for the object center (green) while taking into account the mutal keypoint constellation (red). The object is localized by establishing consensus in the voting behaviour.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consensus-based Matching and Tracking of Keypoints (CMT) is an object tracking algorithm that is able to visually track a wide variety of object classes in a multitude of scenes without the need of adapting the algorithm to specific scenarios in any way. The novelty of our approach is a keypoint-based object representation, where each keypoint votes independently for the location of the object of interest. Experiments have shown that CMT is able to achieve excellent results on a dataset that is as large as 60 sequences. The Python implementation for this work is freely available under the BSD license &lt;a href="https://github.com/gnebehay/CMT"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We congratulate Georg and Roman on this great success and recognition of their work!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2014-03-29:/news/2014-03-29-EPiCS-Article-Aftenposten/</id><title type="html">EPiCS in Norvegian Media</title>
<published>2014-03-28T23:00:00Z</published><updated>2014-03-28T23:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2014-03-29-EPiCS-Article-Aftenposten/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The largest newspaper in Norway, Aftenposten, published on 29 March, 2014 on their web page a popular science article prepared by the EPiCS partner University of Oslo, featuring their work in active music systems in the project. This application is used as an example of novel work in the field of artificial intelligence. The article (in Norwegian) can be found &lt;a href="http://www.aftenposten.no/viten/Liv-i-kunstig-intelligens-7513684.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-10-17:/news/2013-10-17-EPiCS-Video-Challenge-Awards/</id><title type="html">EPiCS Video Student Contest Awards</title>
<published>2013-10-16T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-10-16T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-10-17-EPiCS-Video-Challenge-Awards/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce the winners of the EPiCS Video Student contest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following two videos have been awarded a price:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptive Online Tracker&lt;/strong&gt;  created by Alankar Aryal Atreya (Alpen-Adria Universität Klagenfurt)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Awareness in Technical Systems&lt;/strong&gt;  created by Nadjia Pejic and Jan Krehler (University of Paderborn).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We congratulate the authors of these excellent and entertaining videos for their prizes. Both videos can be watched on the &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/channels/epics"&gt;EPiCS video channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-09-25:/news/2013-09-25-Introduction-to-Ella-Middleware/</id><title type="html">Introduction to the Ella Middleware</title>
<published>2013-09-24T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-09-24T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-09-25-Introduction-to-Ella-Middleware/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have just published an introductory article for the Ella middleware on the Codeproject developer portal. The article covers the basics of publish/subscribe and how to write publishers and subscribers using Ella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/655774/Ella-publish-subscribe-middleware"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-09-01:/news/2013-09-01-FPGA-Heater-Cores-released/</id><title type="html">FPGA Heater Cores released</title>
<published>2013-08-31T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-08-31T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-09-01-FPGA-Heater-Cores-released/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the publication "M. Happe, H. Hangmann, A. Agne, and C. Plessl. &lt;strong&gt;Eight ways to put your FPGA on fire – a systematic study of heat generators.&lt;/strong&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on ReConFigurable Computing and FPGAs (ReConFig), pages 1–8. IEEE Computer Society, Dec. 2012.", which won the best paper award at the ReConFig'2012 conference, University of Paderborn has presented a study on the systematic design and evaluation of circuits that are optimised for generating a maximum amount of heat on FPGAs. Such heater cores can be used for automatically generating and calibrating thermal models of FPGA devices. Also the heater cores can be used to expose distinct areas of the devices to high temperatures with the objective to induce soft-errors, due to an increase in switching time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the heater cores available for other researchers for experimentation, we have released them as pcore modules, that can be integrated as components in Xilinx FPGA designs. The amount of heat that is generated can be adjusted in 32 levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information and the MIT-licensed open source code of the FPGA heater cores can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.epics-project.eu/fpga-heater"&gt;http://www.epics-project.eu/fpga-heater&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-08-20:/news/2013-08-01-Video-Challenge/</id><title type="html">Deadline for EPiCS Video Student Contest extended</title>
<published>2013-08-19T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-08-19T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-08-01-Video-Challenge/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have extended the deadline for submissions to the &lt;strong&gt;EPiCS Video Student Contest&lt;/strong&gt; to August 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this challenge we invite students to produce a short video that explains the role of self-awareness in technical systems. The best video will be awarded with cash prices up to 500€.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information can be found &lt;a href="/contest"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-08-12:/news/2013-08-12-EPiCS-Video-Channel/</id><title type="html">EPiCS Video Channel</title>
<published>2013-08-11T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-08-11T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-08-12-EPiCS-Video-Channel/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that the EPiCS consortium has setup an &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/channels/epics"&gt;EPiCS video channel&lt;/a&gt; at Vimeo, where we share videos for demonstrating and disseminating our research results to a broad audience. The first couple of videos have been already published and several new videos are currently in production. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-08-09:/news/2013-08-09-Peter-Lewis-Exchange/</id><title type="html">Research Exchange of Peter Lewis with Politecnico di Milano</title>
<published>2013-08-08T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-08-08T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-08-09-Peter-Lewis-Exchange/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Peter Lewis, who is based at the University of Birmingham and works
on the EPiCS project, visited Professor Marco Santambrogio at the NECST
Lab at the Politecnico di Milano on a Research Exchange visit. The
visit took place between the 19th and 21st March 2013, and enabled these
two active researchers in the field of self-aware computing to explore
several collaborations and areas for future research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lewis's work in the EPiCS project has been primarily concerned with
developing concepts and foundations for computational self-awareness. On
the conceptual side, his recent work includes the development of a
psychology-inspired conceptual framework for describing and comparing
computational self-awareness capabilities. On the foundational side, his
work has involved developing and applying novel nature-inspired learning
and adaptation algorithms to realise the vision of computational
self-awareness, e.g. in distributed smart camera networks. This work
forms a core aspect of the EPiCS project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Lewis gave an invited talk, describing the developed conceptual
framework for computational self-awareness and how the capabilities it
describes it could be implemented. The talk generated a lively
discussion amongst researchers and students from disparate backgrounds
including electronic and computer engineering, context aware systems,
bioengineering and control theory. Several collaboration scoping
sessions were conducted, with researchers from a range of fields. In
particular, focus areas included how to apply meta-self-aware algorithm
selection to a self-adaptive fault tolerance problem, and the
relationship between computational self-awareness, context awareness and
control theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="/news/fig/peter-lewis-talk.jpg" width="72%" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: left;"&gt;Peter Lewis is giving an invited talk describing the developed conceptual
framework for computational self-awareness and how the capabilities it describes it could be implemented.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-08-07:/news/2013-08-07-Ella-Released/</id><title type="html">Ella distributed publish/subscribe middleware released</title>
<published>2013-08-06T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-08-06T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-08-07-Ella-Released/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ella, the Middleware developed in the EPiCS Project, has just been released as open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ella is a fully distributed publish/subscribe middleware enabling rapid development of data-driven distributed applications. Ella features a simple and fluent facade making it easy to use. A special focus in the design of the middleware has been put easy integration of Ella into existing code. It does not require any inheritance but instead uses code annotations to make classes suitable for use in the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ella can be downloaded from &lt;a href="http://ella.codeplex.com"&gt;http://ella.codeplex.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-08-06:/news/2013-08-06-CAMSIM-Released/</id><title type="html">CamSim simulator for distributed camera networks released</title>
<published>2013-08-05T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-08-05T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-08-06-CAMSIM-Released/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://epics.github.io/CamSim"&gt;CamSim&lt;/a&gt;, the simulator for distributed smart camera networks, has just been released in its first version. In the last few months, the pre-release of CamSim went through various major refactoring processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="center"&gt;
  &lt;iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/70176909" width="500" height="292" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The key changes as well as benefits of CamSim are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Ease of generating test scenarios, with cameras and objects limited only by computer memory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Camera behaviour, using an economic and pheromone inspired approach is implemented, as well as several communication policies. These approaches and communication policies are described in &lt;a href="/publications/2013_esterle_tosn.pdf"&gt;Socio-Economic Vision Graph Generation and Handover in Distributed Smart Camera Networks&lt;/a&gt; by Lukas Esterle, Peter R. Lewis, Xin Yao and Bernhard Rinner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Several bandit solvers are implemented to provide meta-management at the camera level, selecting between communication policies and auction strategies dynamically at runtime. This behaviour is described in &lt;a href="/publications/2013_lewis_saso.pdf"&gt;Learning to be Different: Heterogeneity and Efficiency in Distributed Smart Camera Networks&lt;/a&gt; by Peter R. Lewis, Lukas Esterle, Arjun Chandra, Bernhard Rinner and Xin Yao.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The motion behaviour of objects can be replaced using reflection mechanism. Besides prior known movements 'straight' and 'waypoints', where 'straight' defines movement in a straight line and random bouncing off the simulation boundary and 'waypoints' defines a movement along a predefined  path, another movement behaviour based on Brownian motion has been added to the collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; All aspects of camera behaviour, including bandit solvers, communication strategies and pheromone learning can be replaced using reflection mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To provide prospective developers with a low entrance level, abstract classes are available for extension. Furthermore, introductory tutorials are available online at the GitHub Repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first release can be downloaded from &lt;a href="https://github.com/EPiCS/CamSim/releases/tag/v1.0"&gt;https://github.com/EPiCS/CamSim/releases/tag/v1.0&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-08-01:/news/2013-08-20-Video-Challenge-Extended/</id><title type="html">EPiCS Video Student Contest, win 500€ in cash!</title>
<published>2013-07-31T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-07-31T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-08-20-Video-Challenge-Extended/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that &lt;strong&gt;EPiCS Video Student Contest&lt;/strong&gt;. In this challenge we invite students to produce a short video that explains the role of self-awareness in technical systems. The best video will be awarded with cash prices up to 500€.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information can be found &lt;a href="/contest"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-07-15:/news/2013-07-15-Tatiana-Djaba-Nya/</id><title type="html">Tatiana Djaba Nya joins the EPiCS team at EADS</title>
<published>2013-07-14T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-07-14T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-07-15-Tatiana-Djaba-Nya/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/news/tatiana.jpg" width="200" style="float:right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a postgraduate at EADS Innovation Work in Ottobrunn (Germany) since June 2013.
"Software-centric fault tolerance approaches based on statistical signatures for technical aeronautic systems"
is the subject of my doctoral thesis and it is under the supervision of Dr. Stephan Stilkerich at EADS IW in Ottobrunn
and Professor Christian Siemers at the technical university of Clausthal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until June 2013, I was studying information technology at the technical university of Clausthal. I completed my diploma
thesis at EADS IW in Ottobrunn on the topic "simulation system for proprioceptive computing nodes". I am a holder of
an engineer’s diploma.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2013-06-06:/news/2013-06-06-Caine-Award-Nomination/</id><title type="html">Horatio Caine shortlisted for CREST BSc Final Year Project Award</title>
<published>2013-06-05T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2013-06-05T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2013-06-06-Caine-Award-Nomination/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that Horatio Caine has been shortlisted for the CREST annual prize for the &lt;a href="http://www0.cs.ucl.ac.uk/staff/Yuanyuan.Zhang/BSC/index.html"&gt;BSc Final Year Computer Science Project of the Year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horatio has just completed his BSc in Computer Science at the University of Birmingham, UK, where he collaborated with members of the EPiCS project on his Final Year Project entitled 'Prediction and Classification for Optimisation of Object Tracking in Market-Based Networks of Distributed Smart Cameras'.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CREST centre at UCL accepted submissions from undergraduates in Computer Science from around the UK. Shortlisted candidates win a small cash prize, and will present their projects at a student conference in London on the 25th and 26th of June, which includes a keynote presentation by Microsoft and a champagne reception in a private capsule on the London Eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horatio is staying as a Research Associate at EPiCS for the summer to continue the work he has done with us so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure style="text-align: center;"&gt;
&lt;img src="/news/fig/cain-bsc-award-illustration.png" width="72%" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption style="text-align: left;"&gt;Object trajectories are analysed to perform classification, which allows cameras to communicate more efficiently. Here, Camera B can distinguish between objects heading in different directions to ensure only Camera A uses computational resources searching for the blue object. The addition of classification increases efficiency of multi-camera tracking relative to the state of the art.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2012-12-03:/news/2012-12-03-Reconfig-Award/</id><title type="html">EPiCS team at UPB wins best paper award a the Int. Conference on Reconfigurable Computing and FPGAs</title>
<published>2012-12-02T23:00:00Z</published><updated>2012-12-02T23:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2012-12-03-Reconfig-Award/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that Markus Happe, Hendrik Hangmann, Andreas Agne, and Christian Plessl from the EPiCS team at University of Paderborn have been awarded with the best paper award at the International Conference on Reconfigurable Computing and FPGAs for their paper &lt;a href="/publications/2012_happe_reconfig.pdf"&gt;Eight ways to put your FPGA on fire – a systematic study of heat generators&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2012-10-19:/news/2012-10-19-Borkmann-VDI-Award/</id><title type="html">Daniel Borkmann wins VDI award for his Master's thesis</title>
<published>2012-10-18T22:00:00Z</published><updated>2012-10-18T22:00:00Z</updated><link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2012-10-19-Borkmann-VDI-Award/">
<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/news/borkmann-award.jpg" style="float:right;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that Daniel Borkmann who is part of the EPiCS team at ETH Zurich, has been awarded the 1. Förderpreis Award by the Association of Germany Engineers (VDI) for his Master's thesis &lt;a href="/publications/2012_borkmann_mastersthesis.pdf"&gt;Lightweight Autonomic Network Architecture&lt;/a&gt;. Daniel's Master's Thesis has been submitted to the &lt;a href="http://www.htwk-leipzig.de/en/"&gt;Leipzig University of Applied Sciences&lt;/a&gt; and was executed in cooperation with ETH Zurich as part of the EPiCS project. The implementation of an adaptive networking stack that has been developed as part of his thesis is the foundation of the self-aware networking and protocol graph architecture in EPiCS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We congratulate Daniel on this great success and recognition of his work!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>