<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://www.epics-project.eu/</id>
  <title>EPiCS News</title>
  <updated>2012-04-09T22:00:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/"/>
  <link rel="self" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/atom.xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>The EPiCS Consortium</name>
    <uri>http://www.epics-project.eu</uri>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2012-04-10:/news/2012-04-10-Awareness-Magazine/</id>
    <title type="html">EPiCS article on "Self-Awareness in Computing Systems" in Awareness Magazine</title>
    <published>2012-04-09T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2012-04-09T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2012-04-10-Awareness-Magazine/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Peter Lewis, Xin Yao and Marco Platzner have contributed an article named &lt;a href="http://www.awareness-mag.eu/view.php?source=004093-2012-03-19"&gt;An outlook for self-awareness in computing systems&lt;/a&gt; to the Awareness Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2011-09-02:/news/2011-09-02-EPiCS-Papers-FPL/</id>
    <title type="html">EPiCS presentations at FPL'11</title>
    <published>2011-09-01T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2011-09-01T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2011-09-02-EPiCS-Papers-FPL/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EPiCS consortium will be well represented at the International Conference for Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL'11), which will be held from September 5-7 in Chania, Crete. The following papers will be presented as talks or in poster sessions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A. Agne, M. Platzner, and E. Lübbers. &lt;em&gt;Memory virtualization for multithreaded reconfigurable hardware.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T. Becker, Q. Liu, W. Luk, G. Nebehay, and R. Pflugfelder. &lt;em&gt;Hardware-accelerated object tracking.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;M. Happe and E. Lübbers. &lt;em&gt;A hybrid multi-core architecture for real-time video tracking.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q. Jin, W. Luk, and D. Thomas. &lt;em&gt;Unifying option-pricing designs for hardware acceleration.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X. Y. Niu, K. H. Tsoi, and W. Luk. &lt;em&gt;Reconfiguring distributed applications in FPGA accelerated cluster with wireless networking.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you are attending FPL, we invite you to seize the opportunity to discuss with the presenters about the EPiCS project.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2011-08-18:/news/2011-08-18-more-publication-updates/</id>
    <title type="html">Another major update to the publication list</title>
    <published>2011-08-17T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2011-08-17T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2011-08-18-more-publication-updates/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have added the following publications to the EPiCS publication list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;G. Chow, K. Kwok, W. Luk, and P. Leong. &lt;em&gt;Mixed precision comparison in reconfigurable systems.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. IEEE Symp. on Field-Programmable Custom Computing Machines (FCCM), pages 17–24. IEEE, May 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;S. Denholm, K. H. Tsoi, P. Pietzuch, and W. Luk. &lt;em&gt;CusComNet: a customisable network for reconfigurable heterogeneous clusters.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. IEEE Int. Conf. on Application-Specific Systems, Architectures, and Processors (ASAP), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q. Jin, W. Luk, and D. Thomas. &lt;em&gt;Unifying option-pricing designs for hardware acceleration.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. Int. Conf. on Field Programmable Logic and Applications (FPL), Sept. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Q. Jin, W. Luk, and D. B. Thomas. &lt;em&gt;On comparing financial option price solvers on FPGA.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. IEEE Symp. on Field-Programmable Custom Computing Machines (FCCM), pages 89–92. IEEE, Apr. 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A. Keller, D. Borkmann, and W. Mühlbauer. &lt;em&gt;Efficient implementation of dynamic protocol stacks.&lt;/em&gt; In Proc. ACM/IEEE Symp. on Architecture for Networking and Communications Systems (ANCS). IEEE, Oct. 2011. To appear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For details please refer to our &lt;a href="/publications"&gt;publications list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2011-08-09:/news/2011-08-09-publications-updated/</id>
    <title type="html">The list of publications for the EPiCS project has been updated</title>
    <published>2011-08-08T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2011-08-08T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2011-08-09-publications-updated/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The list of publications has been updated, see &lt;a href="/publications"&gt;publications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2011-03-15:/news/2011-03-15-New-Website/</id>
    <title type="html">The EPiCS project has a new website</title>
    <published>2011-03-14T23:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2011-03-14T23:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2011-03-15-New-Website/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The EPiCS project has a new website, which has been designed by &lt;a href="http://www.goldmarie-design.de"&gt;Goldmarie Design Münster, Germany&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:www.epics-project.eu,2010-12-20:/news/2010-12-20-Publication-Futurenet/</id>
    <title type="html">First EPiCS publication at the IEEE FutureNet'11 workshop</title>
    <published>2010-12-19T23:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2010-12-19T23:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://www.epics-project.eu/news/2010-12-20-Publication-Futurenet/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that the first publication resulting from the EPiCS project has been presented at the IEEE Globecom Workshop on Network of the Future (FutureNet).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
